Guide to the George Healey papers, 1941-1972.
Healey, George papers, 1941-1972.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Healey papers, 1941-1972.
13-6-1969
George Harris Healey, 1908-1971.
9.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, sheet catalogs, manuscripts, newspapers, magazines, and subscription records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Library Journal records include orders/paid subscriptions, 1967-1968 and correspondence, 1966-1972. Also, George James Hucker correspondence regarding the ordering and making of the Cornell University mace, 1961-1963; Rare Books Department correspondence, 1968-1970; sheet catalogs; author's manuscripts, 1966-1972; and a photocopied typescript of a poem written by George H. Healey for the Cornell Class of 1909 Reunion Social, 1963. Includes historical newspapers and magazines regarding World War II and other great moments in twentieth century American history.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
George H. Healey attended West Virginia University, where he received a bachelor's degree in philosophy in 1932 and a master's degree in 1935. In 1940 he became an instructor at Cornell University, and received his Ph.D. from that institution in 1947. He became curator of the Department of Rare Books at its inception in 1957, and continued to teach English at Cornell. Healey published books on William Wordsworth, James Joyce, and Daniel Defoe while developing collections of their works and papers for the Rare Books Department at Cornell.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Cornell Library Journal records include orders/paid subscriptions, 1967-1968 and correspondence, 1966-1972. Also, George James Hucker correspondence regarding the ordering and making of the Cornell University mace, 1961-1963; Rare Books Department correspondence, 1968-1970; sheet catalogs; author's manuscripts, 1966-1972; and a photocopied typescript of a poem written by George H. Healey for the Cornell Class of 1909 Reunion Social, 1963. Includes historical newspapers and magazines regarding World War II and other great moments in twentieth century American history.
Includes correspondence, lectures, speeches, notes, subject files, and University memorabilia.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Healey, George Harris, 1908-1971.; Hucker, George James.; Cornell University. Libraries. Dept. of Rare Books.
Titles:
Cornell library journal.
Subjects:
College teachers--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Form and Genre Terms:
Poems.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Box 3 "Library Associates material (including C.U. Mace correspondence), 1961-1963" was transferred to Cornell University Library Associates records, #13-6-2599 in 1991.
CONTAINER LIST
- Rare Books, Department of. Correspondence (G.H. Healey and D. Eddy), 1968-1971 (Box 1)
- Cornell Library Journal (includes author's manuscripts) 1966-1975 (Box 2)
- Phi Beta Kappa folder (Box 2)
- Rare Books, Department of. Sheet catalogues, A-K (Box 4)
- Rare Books, Department of. Sheet catalogues, K-Z (Box 5)
- G.H.H.'s poem for Class of '09's 1963 Reunion (Box 5)
- Letters from John Robert Moore, 1942-1960 re: Defoe studies (Box 5)
- Additions (Aug. 1995) (Box 6)
- Additions (Aug. 1995) (Box 7)
- Additions (Aug. 1995) (Box 8)
- Additions (Aug. 1995) (Box 9)
- Additions (Aug. 1995) (Box 10)
- Additions (Aug. 1995) (Box 11)